A Guide to the Papers of Joseph Miller 1840-1938
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Joseph Miller 1840-1938
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7687-f
This collection consists of 95 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This addition to the to the S. Philip Holt Papers was deposited 13 November 1974 by David J. Eood, et al for safekeeping and general historical reference.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the S. Philip Holt Papers, 1840-1938, consists of ninety-five items including correspondence, from 1849 to 1877, of Joseph Miller, Lucilla Wood, and M. A. Harper; Loose leaf business papers, from 1840 to 1914, taken from Joseph Miller's account book; a small stamp collection, from 1914 to 1937; a tinted litho print of the Peale portrait of Thomas Jefferson; and an unidentified photograph of a small girl by the Holsinger Studio.
Contents List
- Correspondence of Joseph Miller, Lucilla Wood, and M. A. Harper taken from the Account Book of Joesph Miller, 1835-1853, 1860-1875 1849-1877, n. d., 16 items
- Loose leaf, enclosures, receipts, and printed material taken from the Account Book of Joseph Miller, 1835-1853, 1860-1874 ca. 1840-ca. 1914, n. d., 35 items
- Tinted Litho print of Peale portrait of Thomas Jefferson n. d., 1 item
- Miscellaneous items 1931-1938, n. d., 8 items
- Unidentified photograph of a small girl, done by Holsinger Studio n. d., 1 item
- Stamp collection, many are foreign stamps, of [Miss Lucilla Franke?] ca. 1914-ca. 1937, 27 items
- Bound Manuscripts
  - Account book of Joseph Miller and Mary Ann Harper 1835-1853, 1860-1874
  - Autograph book of Miss Sabina L. Creigh ca. 1840
  - Account book of Joseph Miller, receipts tipped in 1847-1849
  - Account book of Joseph Miller 1852-1853
  - Inventory of Joseph Miller, Verulam Terrace, London and Farmington, Albemarle County, Virginia ca. 1852-ca. 1874
  - Memo book of dinner menus 1855
  - Account book of dinners, kept by Joseph Miller 1856-1858